<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.5/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.5/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.5.xsd" version="0.5" xml:lang="en">
  <siteinfo>
    <sitename>Wikipedia</sitename>
    <base>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page</base>
    <generator>MediaWiki 1.18wmf1</generator>
    <case>first-letter</case>
    <namespaces>
      <namespace key="-2" case="first-letter">Media</namespace>
      <namespace key="-1" case="first-letter">Special</namespace>
      <namespace key="0" case="first-letter" />
      <namespace key="1" case="first-letter">Talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="2" case="first-letter">User</namespace>
      <namespace key="3" case="first-letter">User talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="4" case="first-letter">Wikipedia</namespace>
      <namespace key="5" case="first-letter">Wikipedia talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="6" case="first-letter">File</namespace>
      <namespace key="7" case="first-letter">File talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="8" case="first-letter">MediaWiki</namespace>
      <namespace key="9" case="first-letter">MediaWiki talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="10" case="first-letter">Template</namespace>
      <namespace key="11" case="first-letter">Template talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="12" case="first-letter">Help</namespace>
      <namespace key="13" case="first-letter">Help talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="14" case="first-letter">Category</namespace>
      <namespace key="15" case="first-letter">Category talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="100" case="first-letter">Portal</namespace>
      <namespace key="101" case="first-letter">Portal talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="108" case="first-letter">Book</namespace>
      <namespace key="109" case="first-letter">Book talk</namespace>
    </namespaces>
  </siteinfo>
  <page>
    <title>Fuji (Spacecraft)</title>
    <id>5207391</id>
    <revision>
      <id>395647839</id>
      <timestamp>2010-11-09T00:39:31Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Rich Farmbrough</username>
        <id>82835</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Delink date fragment or minor clean up using [[Project:AWB|AWB]]</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="4618">'''Fuji''' ('''ふじ''') was a manned [[spacecraft]] of the [[space capsule]] kind, proposed by Japan's [[Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency#History|National Space Development Agency]] (NASDA) Advanced mission Research center in December 2001. The Fuji design was ultimately not adopted.

==Background==

In [[Japan]], manned space flight prior to 2001 had depended on the [[United States|USA]] [[Space Shuttle program]], and independent development of spacecraft was not adopted as a short to mid-term goal. Instead, NASDA choose to recommend use of [[Reusable Launch Systems]] with wings such as the US [[Space Shuttle]] and [[HOPE-X|HOPE]].

However,  after the Japanese government reorganized their space exploration efforts under the [[Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency]] (JAXA), Fuji was proposed as a candidate for space missions. The [[Space Shuttle Columbia disaster]] in 2003 also raised questions about the safety of reusable systems, and JAXA felt that the Fuji design, relying on a disposable capsule, would be possible to develop in relatively short span of eight years.

==Design==

The proposed design of Fuji was a modular spacecraft (similar to the [[Gemini spacecraft|Gemini]], [[Apollo spacecraft|Apollo]] and [[Soyuz spacecraft|Soyuz]] spacecraft), with various configurations filling different roles.

===Minimum System===

The Minimum System configuration of Fuji was essentially just a [[Reentry capsule]] with a [[Human spaceflight|manned space flight]] endurance of 24 hours. It was scheduled for development at the early stage of the overall project. This minimum system called the Core Module (CM), and was to be a [[cone (geometry)|cone]]-shaped module with a diameter of 3.7m, gross weight of 3 tonnes or less, and room for a crew of three.  It was to have thrusters for position control and a [[rocket engine]] capable of producing a small amount of thrust. The targeted manufacturing cost was to be about 800 million yen each.

===Standard System===

The Standard System was designed to be capable of flights of one month's duration and into lunar orbit. This system was to consist of the minimum system and two additional modules, an Expansion Module (EM) and a Propulsion Module (PM). The EM was envisioned as a living space, used for a long-term space flights, roughly similar in purpose to the [[Soyuz spacecraft|Soyuz]] spacecraft's Orbital Module (OM). The PM has rocket engine to facilitate orbit changes, and also a [[solar cell]] paddle for production of electricity.

===Economy System===
The design of the Economy System sought to lower the cost of [[Spaceflight|space travel]], and was based on the Minimum System. This system was to be a low cost version of the CM, capable of carrying a pilot and four passengers.

===Other modules===
Additional modules were planned, including a Space Laboratory Module equipped with a heat radiation mechanism, a [[Robotic arm]] module, and an inflatable Simple Life Support Module.

==Features==
The Fuji spacecraft was designed to ensure safety by adopting common existing technologies such as [[Launch escape system|escape rocket]]s and [[Atmospheric_reentry#Ablative|ablative]] heat shields.
 
After reentry, the Fuji capsule was to use a [[parafoil]] and an automatic guidance system based [[Global Positioning System|GPS]] technology for controlled descent and landing.

An [[open architecture]] method was used in development of Fuji to control costs, promote technological development, and to expand the potential market. In particular, the developers disclosed information in the machine/electrical/thermal interface between systems, did not restrict the use of this interface, and provided the test criterion of systems.

In addition, Fuji was not to be limited to the [[H-IIA]] rocket system for launching.

==Advanced Concepts==
A variety of purpose were envisioned for the Fuji system, including uses for [[Space tourism]], with a [[Space station]], and flights to the [[moon]] or [[asteroid]]s

==See also==
*[[H-IIA]]
*[[HOPE-X|H-II Orbiting Plan]] (HOPE)
*[[Soyuz spacecraft]]

==External links==
* {{Wayback|url=giken.tksc.nasda.go.jp/Group/sentan/|title=NASDA Advanced mission Research center (Japanese)|date=20040603193127}}
* [http://www.shokabo.co.jp/author/8758/ Wallpaper of the Fuji Spacecraft] (Japanese)

==References==
*Sinya Matsuura. &quot;われらの有人宇宙船 -日本独自の宇宙輸送システム「ふじ」-&quot;, shokabo, 2003. ISBN 4-7853-8758-0

[[Category:Manned spacecraft]]
[[Category:Proposed spacecraft]]
[[Category:Japanese space program]]

[[ja:ふじ (宇宙船)]]
[[zh:富士號太空船]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
